翻译：草草  CS漫画家小明  菲力  帆大大  王大可  香茗小焙
翻译：鱼小姐啦  某羽   校对：某羽  菲力
时间轴：若林   永远  今
后期：丁丁  斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第四季   第十三集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits
你的名字挂在墙上了
You got your name on the wall.
现在我想要与之匹配的尊重
Now I want the respect that comes with it.
意思是
Meaning?
我想要哈维的一个客户
I want one of Harvey's clients.
我的客户就是我的客户
My clients are my clients.
如果你不在三秒钟内
And you don't get out of my office
离开我的办公室
in the next three seconds,
你我之间一定有事发生
something's gonna happen between you and me,
而且我保证  此事一旦发生
and I guarantee it won't end with you
你的牙肯定保不全
keeping all of your teeth.
艾弗里·麦肯诺曾经是
Avery McKernon was the first client
我带进律所的第一位客户
I ever brought into the firm.
他们总是赢家  就像我
They win, like me.
他们知道特雷弗不是那个班里的
They know Trevor isn't in the class,
所以他不可能是偷试题的那个人
so they know he couldn't have been the one to steal the test.
我不开除你的朋友
I'm not going to expel your friend.
非常感谢您  先生
Oh, thank you, sir.
但是有一点
There's just one thing.
我就打电话给哈佛
I'm gonna call Harvard.
你听我说
Believe me when I tell you,
你是永远去不了哈佛了
You're never going there.
记得这个吗
Remember this?
不  你不记得
No, you don't,
因为你不可能记得没见过的东西
because you can't remember something you never knew.
你不能解雇我
You can't fire me.
我为什么要解雇你  我可以击溃你
Why would I fire you when I can break you?
我要把你埋在一大堆破烂底下
You see, I'm going to bury you under a mountain of shit so big
你会求我把它挪走
you're going to be begging me to take it off.
先那杯曼哈顿给我
First of all, give me that Manhattan
再去点一杯男人会点的酒
and go get yourself a drink a man would order.
15分钟后回来
Come back here in 15 minutes,
如果我还记得你是谁  我就
and if I still remember who you are, I'll be shocked.
好了  我们到底来这儿干什么
Okay, so why are we really here?
你带我出来
I mean, you didn't just bring me
不会只是为了聊卡丽熙吧
out to talk about Khaleesi.
就是啊  保罗·波特说我长得像她的侍女翻译
I did. Paul Porter says I look like her translator.
他也是冰火粉啊
He's a Throner?
不过他说我不如她的小翻译性感
Though he says I'm a less-attractive version of her translator.
好吧  你只是想让我说
Okay, you're just trying to get me to say
你比她性感
that you're hotter than her.
-我是不是嘛  -你性感多了
- Am I? - You're way hotter.
但她口音很撩人
But she has that accent.
我实事求是
Fair point.
好吧  我带你来这儿
You know, look, the reason that I brought you here
是想告诉你  我知道你告诉路易
is to tell you that I know that you told Louis
我给卡特里娜找了份工作
that I got Katrina a job.
-听我说  -别担心  我没生你气
- Look, I -- - Relax, I'm not mad at you.
但我记得是你
But I do remember you being the person
告诉我不要强求
who told me not to force things
-求不来的东西  -瑞秋
- that weren't meant to be. - Rachel,
一个人给别人建议
just because a person gives advice
不代表自己一定会遵守
doesn't mean that they have to follow that same advice.
这是《唐娜之书》的核心原则之一
That's one of the core principles outlined in "The Book of Donna."
说真的  我也不是有意告诉路易的
Seriously, though, I didn't mean to tell Louis.
就是脱口而出了  抱歉
It just came out. I'm sorry.
我说了  没事
Like I said, it's fine.
他其实还来问我们能不能重新做朋友
He actually ended up asking if we could be friends again.
然后呢
And?
我跟他说  我们之间不可能和好如初
And I told him that things would never be the same between us
除非他原谅迈克
unless he forgave Mike.
他怎么说
And what did he say?
他说他做不到
He said he couldn't do it.
简单  过埃卢跳投
That's easy. The jumper over Ehlo.
错  换手单手上篮  过珀金斯和格林
Wrong, the switch-hand layup over Perkins and Green.
你真让我吃惊啊  哈维
I'm surprised at you, Harvey.
过埃卢跳投足以拿下比赛
The Ehlo jumper was a game-winner.
单手上篮是种挑衅
The layup was a statement.
"我想干什么都行  这比赛我赢定了"
"I can do whatever I want. I own this league."
你是在说乔丹还是你自己
Are you talking about Jordan or yourself now?
有区别吗
Is there a difference?
区别大了
A big difference,
这就要说到我来的原因
which brings me to why I'm here.
你不能随心所欲  哈维
You can't do whatever you want, Harvey.
你要我跟路易修好
You want me to make things right with Louis.
他帮助了我和杰夫
He made things right between Jeff and me.
那我就要为此永远巴结他吗
So I'm supposed to kiss his ass forever because of that?
不  你要跟他和好
No, you're supposed to make peace.
杰西卡  我乐意和好
Jessica, I'm willing to make peace,
但那是不可能的
but that's never gonna happen.
为什么
Why not?
因为路易是绝不会原谅迈克的
Because Louis is never gonna forgive Mike.
那就想办法让他原谅迈克
Then figure out a way to make him forgive Mike.
六年前
唐娜  我说过多少次了
Donna, how many times have I told you
你要坐在外面
I want you out front?
我是唯一有秘书的初级律师
I'm the only associate with a secretary.
我希望人们都看到我的秘书
It would be nice if people could see my secretary.
那让你的下任秘书  想办法不进你办公室
Well, then maybe your next secretary can figure out
把这个放好吧
where to put this without coming into your office.
-开玩笑吧  -没有
- You're kidding? - Not kidding.
这不是你伪造的吗
You didn't forge this?
我很厉害  但我不是禽兽
I am a lot of things, but I am not a monster.
我既不会这么对迈克尔也不会这么对你
I would do that to neither Michael nor you.
-叫这么亲啊  -他直呼我教名
- Oh, so he's Michael now? - Well, I'm Donna to him.
我也这么喊他  空中传奇大人打电话来时
He's Michael to me, which is what I told His Airness
我就这么说的
when he called.
等等  你不是在开玩笑
Wait a second. You're not kidding.
他跟我签约了
He signed with me?
严格说  是跟我签约了
Well, technically, he signed with me.
我去  唐娜  我们今晚得庆祝啊
Holy shit, Donna. We have to celebrate tonight.
我是要庆祝
Oh, I'm gonna celebrate.
但你呢  得跟路易喝酒
You, on the other hand, are having drinks with Louis.
什么  我们说过了
What? We've been over this.
不论路易什么时候提出要跟我喝酒
Whenever Louis asks to have drinks with me,
永远拒绝他
the answer's always no.
听好我说的话
Listen to the words that I'm saying.
你今晚要去跟路易喝酒
You are getting drinks with Louis tonight.
费尔柴德要退休了
Fairchild's retiring?
费尔柴德死了
Fairchild's dead.
几乎跟乔丹的消息一样棒了
That's almost as good as the Jordan news.
对费尔柴德可不算
Not to Fairchild.
谁管费尔柴德怎么样啊
Who gives a shit about Fairchild?
真正的悲剧是我要跟路易喝酒
The real tragedy is I have to get drinks with Louis.
所以我给你订了一间小众餐厅
Which is why I got you a secluded restaurant
后面的桌子  没人会看到你的
with a table in the back where no one will see you.
过半小时你会打电话来
And you'll call a half an hour in
说有急事要处理吧
and say there's an emergency.
已经准备好了  如果打不通
Already in place, and if I can't get through,
我会让侍者
then I'll just have the waiter
把酒洒在路易身上
spill drinks all over Louis.
-这你也能做到  -拜托
- You could have that done? - Oh, please.
如果我想  可以让
I could have Louis held captive
路易被人关在一间西藏寺院里
in a Tibetan monastery if I wanted to.
我觉得这你做不到...
Yeah, I don't think you have that--
赶紧滚出你办公室吧
Now get the hell out of your office.
我还有工作呢
I got work to do.
打扰  请问能告诉我
Excuse me. Can you tell me where
吉姆·奥唐纳德的办公室在哪吗
Jim O'Donnell's office is?
看情况了  你对移民法有什么了解
That depends. What do you know about immigration law?
是签证问题
What, are we talking visas,
还是想搞定劳工证
or are you trying to process a labor certification?
你懂移民法
You know about immigration law?
谁不知道啊
Doesn't everybody?
好吧  拽哥
Okay, tough guy,
你觉得我的策略如何
what do you think about my strategy on this?
我觉得能赢
I think it's a winner.
为什么
Why is that?
因为人人都知道冈萨雷斯诉马里兰州
Because everyone knows Gonzalez versus State of Maryland
是个了不起的先例  但你这件更好
was a kick-ass precedent, but your case is better.
的确是个了不起的先例
It was a kick-ass precedent,
但我不知道我这个是不是更好
but I'm not sure that my case is better.
绝对是
Oh, it is.
那维特利诉...
Well, what about Viteri versus--
相信我  这个更好
Trust me, it's better.
维特利靠魔法和同情他们的法官才拿下了案子
Viteri needed magic dust and a sympathetic judge to win.
-我们见过吗  -没有
- Have we met? - Nope.
顺说  我叫迈克
But I'm Mike, by the way.
克莱尔
Claire.
你确定吗  你好眼熟
Are you sure? Because you look very familiar.
那可能是因为我一直往这里送快递
Oh, that's probably because I've been delivering packages
都有俩月了
to your office for the last two months.
但你根本不理我[连时间都不肯告诉]
but you haven't given me the time of day,
因为你觉得我配你不够聪明
because you didn't think I was smart enough for you.
9点15分
It's 9:15.
等等  这样管用吗
Wait. That worked?
目前为止还管用  但如果想继续有用
It's working so far, but I'm gonna need to know
你得跟我说说你的详细情况
your full story if it's gonna keep working.
我会跟你说详细情况
Well, I'll tell you the full story
只要你给我你的电话号码
once you give me your phone number.
等我了解了详细情况  就会告诉你我的电话号码
I'll give you my number when I know the full story.
不如这样  我明天晚餐时告诉你
How about this? I'll tell you everything you want to know
你想知道的一切
at dinner tomorrow night.
那样的话
In that case,
我可以带你去吉姆·奥唐纳德的办公室
I'll show you where Jim O'Donnell's office is.
吉姆·奥唐纳德的办公室
Jim O'Donnell's office?
你觉得我刚刚从哪儿来的
Where do you think I just came from?
我要你帮我点忙
I need you do something for me.
行  什么忙
Okay, what is it?
不用管是什么
Never mind what it is.
你要不想回去干我雇你之前的老本行
Unless you want to go back to whatever you were doing
就明早九点到这个地方
before I hired you, you'll be here at 9:00 a.m.
这是你的汽车俱乐部的地址
This is the address for your car club.
对  你记忆力确实好
Oh, yeah, your memory.
我凭你的记忆力也能记住这个
I'd remember this even if I had your memory.
就在我们合作的第一个案子前去过
It was right before our first case together.
没错  麦肯诺汽车公司
You're right, McKernon Motors.
这次一定要准时  系好安全带
So this time be on time and put your seat belt on,
我们要开上记忆的轨道了
because we're about to take a trip down memory lane.
早上好  亲爱的
Morning, sunshine.
-你在干...  -你管这个叫普鲁尼吧
- What are you -- - I think you call it a Prunie.
恭喜啊
Congratulations,
唐娜把我最爱的早餐饮料都告诉你了
Donna told you my favorite breakfast drink,
但那跟南极洲茶的价格有什么关系呢
but what does that have to do with the price of tea in Antarctica?
唐娜还告诉我你被激怒了
Donna also told me that you were pissed,
因为你发现我给了你一个
because you found out I gave you a client
我起初不想要的客户
I didn't want in the first place.
而你觉得这样就能弥补了吗
And you think this is gonna make up for that?
不能  但我想给你麦肯诺汽车一半业务就能
No, but I think giving you 50% of McKernon Motors will.
条件是什么
What's the catch?
条件就是  你我现在马上
The catch is, you and I are about to take a road trip
开车去他们公司总部
to their corporate headquarters right now.
你说真的吗
You serious?
我可不拿麦肯诺汽车公司开玩笑
I don't joke about McKernon Motors,
这点你跟我一样了解
and you know that as well as I do.
敬费尔切尔德
To Fairchild.
敬费尔切尔德  愿主保佑他灵魂安息
To Fairchild. God rest his soul.
去他的灵魂
Screw his soul.
你知道他们现在怎么表达
You know how they say
"天堂又多了一位天使"吗
"Heaven just got another angel"?
他们现在都不这么说了
They ain't saying it now.
你为什么一直看你的手机
Why do you keep checking your phone?
-没什么  我只是  -拜托  我又不傻
- No reason. I just-- - Please, I'm not an idiot.
我们到这儿已经28分钟了  再过2分钟
We've been here 28 minutes, and in 2 minutes,
唐娜就会打电话来说一个预先计划的紧急情况
Donna's gonna call with some preplanned emergency.
-路易  不是...  -听着
- Louis, that's not... - Look
你为什么认为我利用费尔切尔德退休
why do you think I used Fairchild's retirement
好让你跟我一起喝酒
to get you to have drinks with me?
因为你知道我觉得那永远不可能吗
Because you knew I thought it would never happen?
因为他没有法定继承人
Because he doesn't have an heir apparent.
路易  如果你在考虑的事如我所想
Louis, if you're thinking what I think you're thinking--
哈德曼不会让我们之一当资深合伙人的
Hardman's not gonna make one of us senior partner.
我不是说我们之一
I'm not talking about one of us.
我说的是我们俩一起说服哈德曼
I'm talking about both of us convincing Hardman
两个厉害的初级合伙人
that two kick-ass junior partners are worth
跟一个新的高级合伙人一样厉害
as much as one new senior partner.
路易  这是我认识你以来
Louis, that is the best idea
你想出的最好的点子
you've had since I've known you.
是吗
Yeah?
还有一个
Here's another one.
皮尔逊·哈德曼·斯佩克特·利特
你什么时候想出的这个
When did you come up with this one?
你在洗手间浪费掉
When you were in the bathroom wasting
我们这半小时里的7分钟时
7 minutes of our half hour.
你不用接吗
Don't you have to get that?
不  不用
No, I don't.
来喝酒庆祝吧
Let's drink to this.
混蛋
Asshole.
那是唐娜  不是吗
That was Donna, wasn't it?
特雷弗  这太傻了
Trevor, this is so stupid.
一点也不傻  蠢货
It's not stupid, dickhead.
我要你站在房子正中间
I want you to see it for the first time
第一次好好看
from the middle of the room.
这是你的公寓  笨蛋
It's your apartment, assface,
别想再给我抹一脖子口水
and don't even think about giving me a wet Willie.
你把好玩的都毁了
You suck the fun out of everything.
去吧  睁开眼就  蠢咖
Go ahead. Open your eyes, dickfoot.
-蠢咖  -我本想说笨蛋
- "Dickfoot"? - I was gonna use "Assface."
我只能想到这些
It's all I could think of.
你进社会要怎么办啊
How do you even manage in the world?
你打算继续站在那里闭着眼睛
Are you just gonna stand there with your your eyes closed
嘲笑我的蠢咖吗
and mock my "Dickfoot"?
我才不要睁眼看你的蠢咖
I'm definitely not gonna open them to see your dickfoot.
这倒是说得不错  我也不要
That's a good point. I wouldn't do that either.
快点  睁开眼睛
Go ahead. Open your eyes.
老天呐
Holy shit.
我以为你在弄工作室
I thought you were getting a studio.
是啊  我本来是这么打算  但我发现
Yeah, I was going to, but then I realized
我们不可能一起住在工作室里
we can't both live in a studio.
什么
What?
欢迎光临埃文斯和罗斯之家
Welcome to Casa Evans and Ross.
特雷弗  我付不起一半的房租
Trevor, I can't afford half this rent.
这就是最棒的地方
That's the best part.
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
第一年我会把你的房租全付了
I'm gonna pay for your whole first year.
不  不行  我不能让你帮我付
No, you're not. I can't let you do that.
迈克  我这周二开始新工作
Michael, I start my new job on Tuesday.
除此之外  我还可以做我的伙伴家族生意
On top of that, I have my friends and family business on the side.
那不意味着我要接受你的救济
That doesn't mean I'm gonna take charity from you.
听着  你要逼我说出来吗
Look, are you gonna make me say it?
这不是救济
It's not charity.
我大学毕业了  你没有
I graduated, and you didn't,
因为你为我做的事情顶罪
because you took the fall for something I did.
我欠你的
I owe you.
好吧  我再考虑考虑
Okay, I'll think about it.
好吧  同时也考虑一下这个
All right, in the meantime, think about this.
不  不行
No, I can't.
-我今晚有约会  -好吧
- I got a date tonight. - All right.
怪咖  小胡子  还是全部的
Wow, clubfoot, mustache, all of the above?
先是蠢咖  现在又是怪咖
First dickfoot and then clubfoot?
你现在只会说带"咖"字的词了吗
Are words with "foot" all you've got now?
好吧  聪明人
All right, smart guy,
用你的SAT单词来形容那妹子吧
describe her with one of your SAT words.
-大咖  -这才像话
- Bigfoot. - That's what I'm talking about.
准确地说  她真是辣妹
For the record, she's really hot.
我直说吧
Let me get this straight.
你们要我提拔你们作初级合伙人
Instead of promoting an existing partner,
而不是提拔现有合伙人
you want me to make both of you junior partners.
不是"提拔"  我们赢得的
Well, not make us. We've earned it.
赢得合伙人的地位
Earned partnership status?
这对两个五年律师来说
That's a pretty bold statement
可是相当大胆的提议
coming from two fifth-years.
不是随便的五年律师
Not just any fifth-years.
我们是律所史上  两个最棒的五年
We're the best fifth-years this firm has ever seen,
你也知道的
and you know it.
我能问问这是谁的主意吗
May I inquire whose idea this was?
-我们俩的主意  -路易的主意
- It was both of ours. - It was Louis'.
你可真慷慨
That's generous of you
把功劳都给他了
to give him credit.
慷慨的是他主动来找我分享主意
It was generous of him to come to me with the idea.
事实是  我本不想提拔任何合伙人
The truth is, I wasn't gonna make anyone partner.
但我欣赏你们的勇气
But I do like admire your gumption.
所以我想这样
So here's what I'm willing to do.
我会提拔你们其中那个
I will advance one of you
能证明自己值得被提拔的人
if you prove to me which one it should be.
不  你看  问题是
No, see, that's the whole point.
我们是一起的
We came in as a package deal.
你们来找我提价
You came in with a proposal.
我还个价  你们要么接受  要么放弃
I'm giving you a counter, and it's take it or leave it.
怎么证明
What sort of proof are we talking about?
去拿下麦肯诺汽车公司
Let's just say McKernon Motors is in play,
拿下他们  就是对自己有力的证明
and landing them could go a long way to making your case.
不行  我们不会...
No way. We're not gonna..
好吧  丹尼尔
All right, Daniel.
你要麦肯诺
You want McKernon?
我会给你麦肯诺
I'll get you McKernon.
我们要去麦肯诺汽车公司  不是你的高中舞会
We're going to McKernon Motors, not your senior prom.
为什么我们不能做个车辆服务
Why can't we just take the car service?
因为我们是要去见发动机制造商
Because we're going to an engine manufacturer.
我们得开一辆炫车去
We need to show up with a bad-ass car.
这辆酷车怎么样
How about this little bad boy right here?
不好
That's no good.
怎么不好
Why the hell not?
因为不只是我们两个人去
Because it's not just the two of us.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你这混蛋
You son of a bitch.
你说你和我两人去
You said you and I are going up there.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
如果不那么说  你是不会来的
Because if I didn't, you would have never agreed to come.
我不去了
There is no way I'm going.
你要去
Yes, you are.
有必要的话我会把你绑在车顶上带去
I don't care if I have to tie you to the roof.
去麦肯诺的这段时间
By the time we get to McKernon,
你和迈克要把问题好好解决掉
you and Mike are gonna work your shit out.
难以置信  你居然那么做事
I can't believe you did that.
我们的计划是建立统一战线
The plan was to present a united front.
我们建立了  但他不买账
And we did, and he didn't go for it.
那你就倒打我一耙吗
Then you stab me in the back?
我没有倒打一耙  我接受了他给的条件
I didn't stab you in the back. I took what he gave us.
他什么都没给  哈维
He didn't give us anything, Harvey.
他挑拨我们反目
He pitted us against each other.
路易  咱俩第一天见面起
Louis, we've been pitted against each other
就是对手了
since day one.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
跟我们一起进公司的五十名律师
How many of the 50 associates we started with
你觉得有多少人能当合伙人
do you think are gonna make partner?
我不管其他律师
I don't give a shit about the other associates.
我们为统一战线而干了杯
We toasted to making partner together.
规则不是我定的  路易  哈德曼定的
I don't make the rules, Louis. Hardman does.
尽管我们骂他混球
And as much as we say he's an asshole,
我也尊敬他这种有事明说做法
I respect him for at least telling us the deal out loud.
你喜欢有事明说
You want something out loud?
那我就跟你明说
I'm gonna give you something out loud.
我是不会让你拿到麦肯诺汽车公司的
No way on Earth am I gonna let you land McKernon Motors.
-干什么  -什么干什么
- Hey, what the hell? - What the hell what?
这可不是在兜风  路易
This isn't a joyride, Louis.
你要是不想谈话  就得安静坐着
You don't want to talk, you're gonna sit in silence
直到你准备开口
until you're ready to talk.
你可以让我安静坐着
Well, you can make me sit in silence all you want,
但你不能强迫我跟他合作
but you can't make me work it out with him.
-怎样才能让你跟他合作  路易  -什么
- Then what can, Louis? - Excuse me?
你跟唐娜  跟瑞秋都和好了
You worked it out with Donna and Rachel.
你为了杰西卡跟马龙撒了谎
You lied to Malone for Jessica.
你到底要怎么样才能跟我和好
What's it gonna take to work it out with me?
我原谅了他们  因为他们也是受害者
Well, I forgave those people, because they were victims
他们也被名叫迈克·罗斯的疾病传染了
infected with the disease known as Mike Ross.
如今我不得不跟零号病人一起坐在车里
Now I'm stuck in a car with patient zero.
好吧  疾病爆发  零号病人是第一个
Okay, outbreak, patient zero is the first person
感染疾病的人
actually infected with the disease,
而非疾病本身  提醒你一下
not the disease itself, and for your information,
我也跟你一样困在这车里
I'm stuck in the same car as you.
至少你不用看到
At least you don't have to look at
你自己那个愚蠢的
the back of your own stupid,
肥嘟嘟的秃脑袋
fat, balding head.
有什么可笑的
What's so goddamn funny?
你们终于说话了
You two are finally talking.
奖励你一些音乐
I think you earned a little music.
-就这样  -是啊
- That's it? - Yeah.
你只需要从这两个角色里挑一个
All you have to do is pick one of two characters.
而被我遗弃的那个角色
And whichever character I don't pick
就会被从电影史上永远抹杀
is removed from film history forever?
就像从没存在过一样
It's like they never existed.
小菜一碟
It's a piece of cake.
好吧  汉·索罗或者印第安纳·琼斯
Okay, Han Solo or Indiana Jones?
-不玩了  -怎么了
- I'm out. - What's the problem?
你刚刚还说小菜一碟呢
You just said it was gonna be a piece of cake.
问题是你挑了两个有史以来
The problem is, you just picked the two greatest characters
最棒的角色  所以...
of all time, so...
你说得对  抱歉
You're right about that. I'm sorry.
我说个简单点的
Let me start with something easier for you.
-好吧  -布奇或圣丹斯
- All right. - Butch or Sundance?
分别是《星球大战》和《夺宝奇兵》中的角色
结账
Mm, check, please.
到此为止了
Yeah, we're done.
不
No.
感觉真好
This is really nice.
是的  我也很开心
Yeah, I'm having a really good time too.
什么时候告诉我  你除了送快递
So when do I get to hear the answer to what you do
还做什么
besides being a bike messenger?
谁说我做别的事了
Who says I do anything?
听着  迈克  快递没什么不好
Look, Mike, there's nothing wrong
但是  我对自己的人生很严肃
with being a bike messenger, but I'm serious about my life.
我去法学院并不是为了钱
I'm not going to law school just to cash out.
我真心想帮助别人
I really want to help people.
快递就不能帮助别人吗
Bike messengers don't help people?
我不希望自己恋爱的对象
No, not in the way that a man I want to be
只用这种方法帮助别人
in a relationship with does.
那么  今天你走运了
Well, then today is your lucky day.
我就知道  你要上那个学校
I knew it. Where do you go?
你先说  你要上哪个
Mm-mm, you first. Where do you go?
-纽约大学  -哥伦比亚大学
- NYU. - Columbia.
-我赢了  -我赢了
- I win. - I win.
-早上好  杰西卡  -你好  丹尼尔
- Good morning, Jessica. - Hi, Daniel.
-我还没收到...  -今年的预算吗
- I still haven't received-- - This year's budget?
我正要给你送去呢
I was just on my way to give it to you.
我还以为你一直忙着
And I thought maybe you hadn't gotten around to it
挑拨哈维和路易  没时间做预算呢
because you were too busy pitting Harvey against Louis.
你反对这样吗
You disapprove.
我不介意来点良性竞争
I don't mind a little healthy competition.
但我介意开合伙人资格的空头支票
But I do mind the empty promise of partnership.
你怎么认为最后会没有回报
What makes you so sure there's no reward at the end?
上次我们讨论这个的时候
The last time we discussed this,
你说哈维还没准备好
you said Harvey wasn't ready.
而你说路易没准备好
And you said Louis wasn't.
我是在给他们机会证明自己
Well, I'm giving them both the chance to prove it.
新合伙人的确定已经提上日程了
So partnership is on the table.
早就提上日程了
Partnership was already on the table.
你怎么认定会是哈维
What makes you so sure it's gonna be Harvey?
因为哈维为了获胜不择手段
Because Harvey will do whatever it takes to win.
如果不择手段是评判标准
If doing whatever it takes is the criteria,
那我赌路易会赢
my money is on Louis.
这话是什么意思
What are you talking about?
我们还是去我办公室接着聊吧
I think we should continue this conversation in my office.
你好  我来给佐坦·富莱斯美斯特森送邮件
Hi, I've got a delivery for a Zoltan Freastmeisterson.
这间办公室可没有叫这个名字的人
I'm afraid there's no one in this office with that name.
你记错了吧
I'm afraid you're mistaken.
-是吗  -没错
- Really? - Yeah.
我敢打赌地球上都没有
Because I'm willing to bet that there's no one on this planet
叫这个名字的人
with that name.
好吧  但如果你告诉我
Okay, fine, but if you could just point me towards
金桔·麦格利卡迪的办公室在哪
Kumquat McGillicuddy's office,
我就不缠着你了
I'll be on my way,
因为我可没有带着两封假邮件
because I certainly did not bike down here
专门骑车过来就是为了告诉你
with two fictitious deliveries just to tell you
我昨晚很开心
what a great time I had last night.
那就好  因为我有一大堆活要干
Good, because I have a lot of work to do.
所以  如果你能跳上你那辆小自行车...
So, if you could please just hop on that little bike of yours--
-克莱尔  -怎么了
- Claire? - Yeah.
等你跟这位快递员调完情
When you're finished flirting with Quicksilver here,
最好去趟移民局
you might want to get down to INS.
海克特·苏雷兹刚刚被带走了
Hector Suarez just got taken in.
见鬼  他的签证到期了
Shit. His visa's expired.
他们会把他遣返回多米尼加共和国的
They're gonna send him back to the Dominican Republic.
等一下  或许我能帮忙
Wait. Maybe I can help.
不是我看不起你  但我觉得你帮不上...
No offense, I don't see how you can--
不  不  纳森  他不光是个送信员
No, no, no, Nathan, he's not just a bike messenger.
他在念法学院
He's in law school.
真的吗
Really?
-那个学校的法学院  -哥伦比亚大学
- Where are you in law school? - Columbia.
他还恰巧比咱俩都了解签证
And he happens to know visas better than either one of us.
但我没法付你钱  所以...
Well, I really can't pay you, so...
不  不用给钱
No, I don't need any money.
我只是想帮忙而已
I just want to help.
好吧  哥伦比亚小伙  看你的了
All right, Columbia, be my guest.
周二早上九点有个听证会
Got a hearing Tuesday morning, 9:00 A.M.
迈克  太好了  谢谢你
Mike, that is amazing. Thank you.
先别急着谢我  我还什么都没...
Oh, no, don't thank me yet. I haven't even done any--
可能跟这事没什么关系  但我今天早上
Um, this might not be relevant, but I actually saved
救了金桔·麦格利卡迪一命  所以...
Kumquat McGillicuddy's life this morning, so...
我得去准备一下了
I'm gonna go do some work.
谢谢
Thank you.
麦肯诺先生  我是哈维·斯佩克特
Mr. McKernon, Harvey Specter.
斯佩克特先生  你能给我解释一下为什么
Mr. Specter, would you mind telling me why I have
我今天要与皮尔逊·哈德曼律所的
two different Pearson Hardman lawyers
两个律师见面吗
on my schedule today?
我不知道  但跟我谈完
I don't know, but after this,
你就不需要见另一个了
you won't need to meet the other one.
你还真是自以为是
You're cocky.
我不说错话
I'm right.
你也没带多少东西来
You're also traveling a little light.
你的幻灯片展示呢
Where's your PowerPoint presentation?
我不需要幻灯片展示
I don't need a PowerPoint presentation.
为什么
Why is that?
因为这座城里每个律师都试过征服你
Because every lawyer in the city has tried to dazzle you,
你却仍在寻找合适的人选
and you're still looking for a date to the big dance,
那是因为他们不知道你看重什么
because they don't know what you're looking for.
你说我看重什么
What exactly am I looking for?
忠诚
Loyalty.
没错
You're right.
我白手起家建立起这间公司
I built this company from the ground up,
跟我共同奋斗的人仍陪在我身旁
and everybody that started with me is still here.
我知道原因
And I know why.
不景气的时候不裁员
You don't downsize in the bad times.
到了好时候他们自然不离不弃
They stick with you in the good times.
别的律师都没想明白这点
And no other lawyer has figured that out.
除了一个人
Not a single one.
那就是我  艾弗里
Well, I'm the one, Avery,
所以我知道你不希望我放弃你
which is why I know you don't want me dumping you
投向另一个更大的客户
for a bigger client down the line.
我怎么知道你不会这么做
How do I know you won't do that?
因为这不是我的工作风格
Because that's not the way I work.
说的倒是好听
Well, it's a hell of a nice sentiment.
但我怎么知道你不是信口雌黄
But how do I know you're not full of shit?
我很高兴你这么问
I'm glad you asked,
因为这就是我的幻灯片
because here's my PowerPoint presentation.
好吧
Okay...
我明天有个听证会  对方是弗莱彻引擎公司
I have a hearing tomorrow against Fletcher Engines.
要是胜诉  你就是我的律师
You win that, you're my lawyer.
别换车道
Ok, just don't change lanes,
don't change lanes.
别换  真棒  好吧  知道吗
Don't do this. Great. Okay, you know what?
太荒唐了  你开车跟个野蛮的动物似的
This is ridiculous. You drive like a savage animal.
路易  男人点  忍着吧
Louis, be a man and suck it up.
忍着  我坐在死亡座椅上
Suck it up? I'm sitting in the death seat.
好吧  我靠边停车  你到后面跟迈克坐
Fine. I'll pull over, and you can sit in the back with Mike.
我可不跟一个骗子坐在后面
Hey, I'm not sitting in the back with a fraud,
你想都别想让他坐前面
and before you even think it, you're not putting him up here
把我塞到后面
and sticking me back there.
那你想怎么办  路易
Then what do you want, Louis?
我不可能让你
Because there is no way in hell
来开车
I'm letting you behind the wheel of this car.
解决办法显而易见
It's crystal goddamn clear.
我们坐在后座  让他当我俩的司机
You and I sit in the back, and he chauffeurs the both of us.
这可不行  就算哈维同意
Whoa, no. Even if Harvey would agree to that,
-我对此深表怀疑  -你闭嘴吧
- which I doubt-- - Shut the hell up.
你没有发言权  没有拒绝的资格
You're not talking. You don't get to refuse.
我不是拒绝  路易  我不会开车
I'm not refusing, Louis. I don't know how to drive.
真他妈见鬼
Holy shit.
你想见我
You wanted to see me?
是的
Uh, yes.
我听说艾弗里·麦肯诺那边你干得不错
I heard you did well with Avery McKernon.
那你可听错了
Well, then you heard wrong,
因为我搞定艾弗里·麦肯诺了
because I killed it with Avery McKernon.
-恭喜你  哈维  -谢谢  丹尼尔
- Congratulations, Harvey. - Thank you, Daniel.
不客气
You're welcome.
不幸的是  我们不能代表麦肯诺马达公司
Unfortunately, we can't represent McKernon Motors after all.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为弗莱彻引擎公司想跟我们签约
Well, it turns out Fletcher Engines wants to sign with us.
因为他们发现我就要拿下麦肯诺
Because they found out I'm about to land McKernon.
没错
Yes,
而且他们规模是麦肯诺汽车公司的三倍
and they're three times the size of McKernon Motors.
我才不管他们规模多大
Well, I don't care how big they are.
我不会放弃我的客户
I'm not dropping my client.
你得放弃
Yes, you are.
你一早就计划好了
This was your plan all along.
没错  这世界就是这样的
Of course it was. That's how the world works.
我不管这世界怎么样
I don't give a shit how the world works.
我向艾弗里·麦肯诺保证过
I gave my word to Avery McKernon.
小心点  哈维
Watch yourself, Harvey.
我走到今天靠的不是小心翼翼  丹尼尔
I haven't gotten where I am by watching myself, Daniel.
我也不喜欢被人用来打掩护
And I don't appreciate being used as a stalking horse.
你可以不喜欢  但我提醒你
Well, you may not appreciate it, but let me remind you,
我是你的老板
you work for me.
我在给你机会证明你懂
And I'm giving you the chance to show me you understand that.
别忘了  你说过要增加合伙人
Let me remind you you said partnership was on the table.
我不会让你食言的  杰西卡也不会
I'm gonna hold you to that, and so will Jessica.
吃屁鬼
Hey, fart taster.
我还以为你会来我家
I thought you were coming over.
怎么了  这个名字很经典
What, nothing? It's a classic.
我是指你的工作就是在...
I'm implying your job is to literally taste--
特雷弗  我正在忙
Hey, Trevor, I'm in the middle of something,
我一会儿去找你好吗
so I'll come over later, okay?
忙什么
In the middle of what?
我跟你提过的那个女孩
That girl I told you about,
她在法律援助所实习
she interns at a legal clinic,
我正在帮她处理一个案子
and I am helping her with a case.
"蠢咖"还给你布置作业了
Dickfoot gave you homework?
第一  从现在开始叫她克莱尔
Okay, first of all, from now on, her name is Claire.
第二  这活儿很重要  所以...
And second of all, this is important, so...
老兄  你在说什么
Dude, what the hell are you talking about?
我好像骗她说我在读法学院
I might have told her that I'm in law school.
我了个去
Holy shit.
为了滚床单你什么都做得出来啊
You will do anything to get laid.
我不是为了滚床单
I am not trying to get laid.
我真的很喜欢这个女孩
I really like this girl,
如果只是个送信的
and I have zero chance with her
我没机会和她在一起
if all I am is a bike messenger.
对  但等她发现你骗她
Yeah, well, you're definitely gonna have no chance
你就更不可能有机会了
if she finds out that you lied to her.
特雷弗  我不想再跟你谈这个了
Trevor, I don't want to talk about this anymore.
你什么都不想再谈了
You don't really want to talk about anything anymore.
和公寓有关  是吗
It's about the apartment, isn't it?
-没错  -好吧  要听实话吗
- Yes it's about the apartment. - Okay, you want the truth?
我没答复你是因为奶奶
I haven't given you an answer because of Grammy.
你以为我不知道
You think I didn't know that?
你也知道她不会原谅你
Then you know she's never forgiven you
大学时做的那些事
for what happened in college,
她是绝对不可能让我和你一起住的
and she is never, ever going to let me live with you.
那就她解释  我是为了
Then explain to her that this is my way
为大学时的错误做补偿
of making up for what I did in college.
没用的
That is never gonna work.
知道吗  迈克尔
You know what, Michael?
如果你能为刚遇见的女孩这么努力
If you're gonna do all of this for some girl you just met,
或许你该在奶奶面前替我说说话了
maybe it's time you stood up to Grammy for me.
和弗莱彻引擎打的怎么样
How'd it go against Fletcher Engines?
把他们打断了腿还是打趴在地
You cut them off at the knees or put them in the ground?
他们把我打趴在地了
They put me in the ground,
更惨的是  还当着艾弗里·麦肯诺的面
and on top of that, it was in front of Avery McKernon.
你败诉了
You lost in court?
不仅败诉  还败得像个傻瓜
I didn't just lose. I looked like a fool.
哈维  怎么了
Harvey, what happened?
弗莱彻引擎公司的律师
The general counsel for Fletcher Engines
早就清楚我的每一步策略
knew every move I was gonna make before I even made it.
这怎么可能...
How could he--
因为哈德曼提醒过他了
Because Hardman must have tipped him off.
你真觉得他会那么做吗
You really think he would do that?
我昨天还不确定  今天非常肯定
I wouldn't have yesterday, but I sure as hell do today.
那你得去找杰西卡
Then you have to go to Jessica.
说什么
And say what?
哈德曼是管理合伙人  而她不是
Hardman's managing partner. She's not.
我没有证据  也不可能拿到
I don't have any proof, and I never will.
那你打算怎么做
Well, then what are you gonna do?
不知道  但我还有不到14个小时
I don't know, but I have less than 14 hours
去翻那1000页的专利权法
to dig through 1,000 pages of patent law.
要是律所里恰好有个精通专利权法的人
If only there was somebody in the office who was an expert
就好了
on patent law.
唐娜  我不会去找路易的
Donna, I am not going to Louis.
他绝对不会帮我
He'll never help me.
那真糟糕  如果你不懂
Well, that's too bad, because if you can't figure out
如何与路易和好如初
how to patch things up with Louis,
那你也配不上艾弗里·麦肯诺这客户
then you don't deserve Avery McKernon
以及合伙人的身份
or that partnership.
这是为了什么
What's all this?
孙子就不能为奶奶点餐到家
Uh, a grandson can't order in and set a table
布置餐具吗
for his grandmother?
孙子想做什么都可以
A grandson can do whatever he wants.
但答案还是不行
But the answer to your question is no.
你还没听我的请求呢
You haven't even heard what it is yet.
我知道是什么  因为我从你一毕业
I know what it is, because I've been waiting for it
就在等你问我
since that kid graduated,
你不能和他一起住
and you are not gonna live with him.
是他害你被学校开除
That boy is the reason you got kicked out of school.
是你让我把实情告诉院长的
You're the one that told me to tell the dean the truth.
那是在我知道你会被开除之前
That was before I knew it would cost you graduating.
他现在想补偿我
And he's trying to make it up to me.
他会替我付一整年的房租
He's gonna pay for my whole first year's rent.
这不能弥补他把你的人生
That will not make up for putting your whole life
搅得天翻地覆
into a tailspin.
-这是好的开始  -不  这不是
- It's a head start. - No, it's not a head start!
那孩子会再次把你拖入泥潭
That boy is gonna drag you back down with him!
奶奶  我不会让这种事发生的
Grammy, I'm never gonna let that happen!
该死的  我不允许
God damn it! I forbid it!
抱歉  迈克尔  我失控了
I'm sorry, Michael. I lost my temper.
但我知道他对你做了什么
But I know what he does to you,
我也知道他不会改变
and I know he'll always be the same.
你想过或许我和以前不一样了吗
Has it occurred to you that maybe I'm not the same?
哪儿不一样了
What's changed?
我遇到了一个人
I met someone.
我会想办法完成学业
And I'm gonna figure out a way to finish school, and...
然后我要去读法学院
and then I'm gonna go to law school.
很好
Good.
那就在这里努力
Then do it from here
你在想什么  迈克
What's on your mind, Mike?
你看起来在沉思
You look lost in thought.
我只是想到了我奶奶
I was just thinking about my grandmother.
我们曾坐火车去过一次特区
We took a train trip to D.C. once.
玩《谁是间谍》的游戏
We played I Spy.
故事很动人  迈克  但我们不会玩的
That's a nice story, Mike, but we are not playing I Spy.
我玩  让我想起去看臭烘烘的芙丽塔的路上
I'll play. It'll remind me of Dominating Esther on our trips
玩的《独裁者以斯帖》
to see our smelly Aunt Frida.
好吧  如果这能让你和迈克说说话
All right, if it will get you and Mike talking, sure.
我侦查到一个骗子
I spy a fraud
他可能从来都不了解自己奶奶
who probably never even knew his grandmother.
够了  你如果对我有意见
All right, God damn it, you got a problem with me,
直接跟我说
take it up with me,
别扯到我奶奶身上
but don't ever talk about my grandmother again.
我差点忘了
Oh, I forgot,
那个从纽约来的可怜孤儿
the poor orphan from New York City
我应该为他从没学过开车而感到同情
who I should feel sorry for because he never learned to drive.
我警告你  管好自己的嘴
I'm telling you, watch yourself.
为什么  因为我伤害你感情了吗
Why? Because I hurt your feelings?
-路易  -我才不在乎呢
- Louis! - I don't care.
据我所知  你可能根本不是个孤儿
For all I know, you're probably not even an orphan.
路易
Louis!
骗子讲这类故事
It sure as hell wouldn't be the first time a con man
可不是第一回了
tried to make that claim.
-够了  -不  不够
- That's enough. - No, it isn't.
确实够了  靠边停车
Yes, it is. Pull the car over right now.
我要好好揍他一顿
I'm gonna beat the shit out of him.
你有空吗
Hey, you got a minute?
等等  让我先转过身
Oh, wait. Let me turn my back,
找个合适的角度让你捅...
so I can give you the right angle to---
你是对的  我们本该团结一致的
You were right. We should have stuck together.
我知道了  你想让我帮忙
I get it-- you need my help,
因为你今天早晨被打了个屁滚尿流
because you got your ass wiped in court this morning.
你说得对  我今天早晨确实被打败了
You're right. I did get my ass kicked this morning,
但那并不是一场公平的战斗
but it wasn't a fair fight.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
哈德曼登陆了我的电脑
Hardman accessed my computer
把我的计划发给了对手
and fed the other side my game plan.
你说的这些
Okay, I'm still waiting for the part
我毫不关心
where I'm supposed to give a shit.
哈德曼这样做是因为我拒绝为了弗莱彻
Hardman did it because I refused to dump McKernon
对我承诺过的麦肯诺食言
for Fletcher after I gave him my word.
你也一直对我食言
And why should I help you
我又为什么要帮你
when you couldn't live up to your word to me?
我没有对你食言
I did live up to my word.
-我们一起去找了丹尼尔  -胡扯
- We went to Daniel-- - Oh, bullshit.
不  这不是胡扯
No, it's not bullshit.
我欣然接受了你的意见
I welcomed your idea with open arms,
而且当他问这是谁的主意时
and by the way, when he asked whose idea it was,
我把功劳全给了你
I gave you the credit.
哈维  这就是你不明白的地方
You see, Harvey, that's the part you will never understand.
我不想要什么功劳
I didn't want the credit.
我想要我们成为一个团队
I wanted us to be a team.
那让我们成为一个团队
Then let's be a team right now.
可你并不真心想要一个团队
But you don't want to be a team.
你想要让我帮你搞定麦肯诺
You want me to help you get McKernon
你好当上合伙人
so you can make partner.
我希望你帮我实现我对艾弗里·麦肯诺的承诺
I want you to help me so I can keep my word to Avery McKernon.
然后等我当上合伙人以后
And when I become partner,
我会严守我对你的承诺
I'll keep my word to you.
什么承诺
What the hell word is that?
承诺有一天你写在餐巾纸上的那些字
That someday what you wrote on that napkin
能够真正挂在那面墙上
goes up on the goddamn wall.
看起来你很用功啊  迈克
You seem to have done a lot of work here, Mike.
没什么大不了的
Oh, it's no big deal.
这很重要
It is a big deal.
迈克在1975年移民法中找到了一个漏洞
Mike found a loophole in the Immigration Act of 1975,
会让你大吃一惊的
and it's gonna blow you away.
那我说不准
I don't know about that,
不过这确实可能帮海克特·苏雷兹留下
but it may help Hector Suarez stay in the country.
那太棒了
That's great.
而且我非常欢迎你留下看庭审情况
And you're more than welcome to stay and watch.
不幸的是  克莱尔
Unfortunately, Claire,
我需要你回办公室一趟
I need you to run back to the office.
马歇尔请病假了
Marshall called in sick.
我需要有人接待无预约委托人  所以
I need someone to handle the walk-ins, so...
好吧
Okay.
打电话告诉我情况怎么样
Call me. Tell me how it goes.
好
Yeah.
你这是在干什么  那...
What the hell are you doing? That's--
帮海克特·苏雷兹留下
Gonna keep Hector Suarez in the country?
是啊
Yeah.
没有任何办法能帮他留下
Yeah, nothing's gonna keep him in the country.
我要做的就是帮他争取一点时间
So what I'm going to do is I'm gonna buy him some time
让他把事情安排好
so he can get his affairs in order,
然后我会争取让他的孩子有机会留下
and then I'm gonna give his children a chance to stay.
我只是...  抱歉
I'm just--I'm--I'm sorry.
你是在嫉妒我和克莱尔吗
Are you jealous of me and Claire or...
我没有嫉妒  而且我一直
Hey, look, I'm not jealous, and I was waiting
等到她离开  免得你尴尬
for her to leave to save you the embarrassment.
尴尬什么
The embarrassment of what?
我的工作做得很好
That's good work.
我说的不是这个
I'm not talking about the work.
我说的是你那套"白天送信
I'm talking about your "bike messenger by day,
晚上上法学院"的胡话
law student by night" bullshit.
你不知道自己在说什么
All right, you don't know what you're talking about.
你接下来还要告诉我什么
What are you gonna tell me next?
你的室友是个上医学院的脱衣舞男吗
Your roommate is a stripper who's in medical school?
告诉我  如果我现在打给哥伦比亚
Tell me right now--I call Columbia,
你的故事能得到证实
your story holds up.
正如我所料
That's what I thought.
别管我是谁  先看看那些文件行吗
Forget who I am, and take a look at that folder.
-这关乎一个人的生活  -别碰我
- This is a man's life. - Don't touch me.
如果你知道为自己好
If you know what's good for you,
就该离克莱尔远远的
you'll stay the hell away from Claire.
丹尼尔
Daniel...
你知不知道有些特殊的品种
Did you know that some of these species
可以活两百年
can live up to 200 years?
太神奇了
Fascinating.
那你知道弗莱彻引擎公司被打得丢盔卸甲吗
Did you know Fletcher Engines is picking up the pieces?
我猜我应该恭喜你
I guess congratulations are in order.
我来不是为了你的表扬
I not here for a pat on the back.
我来是告诉你  你得让我当合伙人
I'm here to tell you you're making me partner.
合伙人
Partner?
我从没说过签下麦肯诺就可以当合伙人
I never said signing McKernon was the key to making partner.
-你说过  -我说的只是签下他们
- Yes, you-- - All I said was landing them could go a long way
会大大增加你的优势
toward making your case.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你说会任命新合伙人
You said partnership was on the table.
而且我说过不会让你食言
And I said I was gonna hold you to it.
现在我就要去
And I'm going to right now.
你没权利让我做任何事情
You don't hold me to anything.
不过我确实说过会决定合伙人
But I did say partnership was on the table,
我也确实做了决定
and it is...
只不过不是你
just not for you.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我总不能在告诉路易让他当合伙人后
Well, I can't very well make you partner
再让你当合伙人吧
after I just told Louis I'm making him partner.
什么
What?
你还不明白  是吗
You don't get it, do you?
这并不在于签下新的委托人
This isn't about bringing in business.
在于找出谁会不惜一切去争取
This is about figuring out who would do whatever it takes.
我不惜一切去争取了
I did whatever it took.
你什么都没做
You didn't do a thing.
只要你愿意做小人
You had the chance to triple our business,
就能把我们的生意扩大两倍
and all you had to do was take a knee.
那叫卑躬屈膝
You mean bend a knee.
是的  我就是指这个
Yes, that's exactly what I mean.
可你就是一个傲慢自大的小男孩
But you're an arrogant little boy
宁愿赢也不愿识时务
who would rather win than get in line.
那路易又怎么识时务了
Well, what the hell did Louis do to get in line?
他付出了一切
He did whatever it took.
-请离我远点  -克莱尔  等等
- Please get away from me. - Claire, wait.
-纳森都告诉我了  -让我解释下  好吗
- Nathan told me everything. - Just let me explain, okay?
解释什么  你是反社会者吗
No, explain what-- that you're a sociopath?
我不是反社会者
I'm not a sociopath.
我是之前跟你很合得来的人啊
I'm the same guy that you hit it off with.
不  你不是  你骗了我
No, you're not. You lied to me.
不  我是  我并不是故意要骗你的
Yes, I am, and I didn't mean to lie to you, okay?
我本是打算告诉你事实的
I was gonna tell you the truth.
那你为什么不说呢
Then why didn't you?
因为你说你的理想型是个
Because you said you wanted to be with a guy
能好好生活  踏实做事的人
who was doing something good with his life,
但我不是
and I wasn't.
那又怎样  你现在是来告诉我说突然之间
So what, now you're here to tell me that all of a sudden,
你就想投身于助人为乐的伟大事业了
you want to dedicate your life to helping people
还是又要撒其他的谎
or some other lie like that?
我没骗你  我本也能帮到海克特·苏雷兹的
It's not a lie, and what I did would have helped Hector Suarez.
是啊  但是你只是为了…
Yeah, but you only did it--
克莱尔  求你了  你得相信我
Claire, please, you have to believe me.
遇见你之后  我就打算要重新做人了
After I met you, I decided to get my shit together.
我正在努力重新开始
I am trying to get my shit together.
好了  迈克  你知道比起
Okay, Mike, you know what I hate more
生活一团糟  我更恨的是什么吗
than guys who don't have their shit together?
就是骗人说你在重新开始
It's guys who lie about getting their shit together.
克莱尔
Claire.
路易  加满油  我马上回来
Louis, fill up the tank. I'll be back.
动手吧
Well?
动什么手
Well, what?
你听到他说的了  加油啊
You heard what he said. Fill up the tank.
对  我的确听到了
Yeah, I did hear what he said.
他说的是  路易  把油加满
He said, "Louis, fill up the tank."
可是  在我们那儿  给车加油这种事
Well, where I come from, it's people who didn't go to college
是没上过大学的人干的
who fill up gas tanks.
嗯  可是在我们那儿
Yeah, and where I come from,
你要是再朝前走一步
if you take another step towards me--
噢  怎样  城里来的小霸王要揍我了吗
Oh, what, the tough kid from the city is gonna beat my ass?
路易  我再警告你一次
Louis, I'm telling you right now...
你毁了我的人生  你还毁了我的律所
You ruined my life. You ruined my firm.
路易
Louis!
贱人
You son of a bitch.
等等  哈维
Wait. Harvey--
现在就告诉我  不是你
Tell me right now you weren't the one
把我的计划透露给了弗莱彻引擎公司
that gave Fletcher Engines my game plan.
哈德曼跟我说  他本来就没想让你做合伙人
Hardman told me he wasn't gonna make you partner anyway.
他把这个机会给我  我只要
And once he offered it to me, all I had to do was--
出卖我
Sell me out.
我现在做的  跟你当初
How is what I did any different than you going after
争麦肯诺汽车公司时有什么区别
McKernon Motors in the first place?
如果你不能自己想明白  那你永远也不会懂
If you don't understand that on your own, you never will.
所以  从现在开始  你走你的阳关道
So, from now on, you stay on your side of the yard.
-我过我的独木桥  -哈维  听我说
- I'll stay on mine. - No, Harvey, listen to me.
你告诉过我只要你能获得地位
You told me you would fight to get our names on the wall
就会为我们的名字上墙而努力
once you got on the other side.
我也可以这样做
I can do the same for you.
你有听到我刚刚说的吗
Did you hear what I just said?
我不想要你为我做什么
I don't want you doing shit for me.
所以你做那个先成功的英雄
Oh, so it would be okay if you were the one
就没有问题了吗
who got there first?
要是你能先成功也可以啊
It would have been okay if you got there first
只要你光明正大
fair and square,
这样等你想跟我齐心协力的时候
because then I would have believed you
我才能相信你
when you said you wanted to be a team.
我的确想跟你齐心协力  哈维
I do want to be a team, Harvey.
所以之后我帮了你
That's why I helped you after.
你没有
No, you don't!
你不想组成团队
You don't want to be a team.
你是想鱼和熊掌兼得
You just want to have it both ways,
因为你是个不忠诚的叛徒
because you're a disloyal rat.
不管你门上贴了什么
You always have been, and you always will,
现在  将来  你都只是个叛徒
no matter what it says on your door.
就像你说的  我们从第一天起
Well, like you said, we've been pitted against each other
就已经是对手
since day one.
你问我当初一起的那50个初级律师
You asked how many of the 50 associates we started with
有多少会变成合伙人
would make partner.
其实  我一点也不在乎剩下的49个人
Well, you know what? I don't give a shit about the other 49,
因为我成为了合伙人
because I'm the one who did.
我  成为了合伙人
I'm the one who did.
现在请你滚远一点
And now get the hell out of my face,
我还有工作要做
because I have work to do.
你知道他是故意的吧
You know he did that on purpose, right?
故意什么
Did what on purpose?
他叫你去加油是因为他知道你会怎么做
He asked you to fill the tank because he knew what you'd do.
知道我会怎么做
Knew what I would do?
怎么不说他知道你会怎么做
What about what you would do?
那个他也知道
He knew that too.
路易
Louis...
你连对不起都没跟我说过
You never even said you were sorry.
对不起  路易
I am sorry, Louis.
很抱歉我骗了你
I'm sorry that I lied to you.
但我不是骗子  路易
I'm not a con man, Louis.
我跟你说的其他事都是真的
Every single other thing I ever told you was true.
想知道点
Want to know something that
我自己都不敢承认的事吗
I've never even admitted to myself?
我没学开车跟我没上法学院
I never learned to drive for the same reason
背后的原因是一样的
I never went to law school.
因为我的双亲死于一场车祸
Both my parents were killed in a car accident.
从那之后  我再也不敢…
And ever since then, I've never been able to--
坐在方向盘前
Get behind the wheel.
后来哈维给我驾照  我也收了
And then Harvey gave me a license, and I took it.
你那时才11岁啊
You were 11 years old.
你肯定觉得很孤独
I mean, you must have felt so alone.
我以为你不相信我是个孤儿呢
I thought you said you didn't believe I was an orphan.
我查过
I looked it up.
一发现你没上过法学院我就忍不住去查了
I had to once I found out that you never went to law school.
你是说一发现我是个骗子么
You mean once you found out that I'm a fraud.
你不是骗子  迈克
You're not a fraud, Mike.
你只是没上过法学院罢了
You just never went to law school.
好啦  弗雷泽[拳击手]  给你葡萄味的
Okay, Frazier, you get a grape.
阿里  给你混合果味的
Ali, I got you a fruit punch.
你们俩和好了吗
You two work your shit out?
就当是了  那我们走吧
I'll take that as a yes. Let's get the hell out of here.
我不该骗她的
I should never have lied to her.
诶  去她的吧  兄弟
Oh, screw her, man.
要是她不喜欢你本来的样子
If she doesn't like you for who you are,
她就不值得拥有你
she doesn't deserve you.
这不是克莱尔的错  是我的错
It's not Claire's fault. It's mine.
我知道你很喜欢她
I know you were into her and everything,
但相信我
but trust me,
天涯何处无芳草
there are plenty of other fish in the sea.
你又不是先知
You don't know that.
就我而言  我不可能再遇到
For all you know, I'm never gonna meet
像她这样的女孩了
another girl like her again.
迈克…
Michael--
特雷弗  要是你想让我听
Trevor, if I'm gonna have to listen
你接下来要说的话
to whatever you're about to say,
那就得先给我来根大麻烟
I'm gonna need a joint first.
天呐  你不是要重新开始人生么
Come on, I thought you were trying to turn your life around.
我明天再重生吧
I'll turn my life around tomorrow.
今晚我还是个送信的  所以…
But tonight I'm a bike messenger, so...
-老兄  -特雷弗
- Dude-- - Trevor.
好吧
All right.
很好
Fine.
我知道奶奶不想让你住这里
And I know Grammy doesn't want you living here,
但你愿意的话  今晚可以留下
but you can crash here tonight if you want.
唐娜
Donna.
出了什么事吗
Something wrong?
为什么你会觉得出事了
Why would something be wrong?
因为我不记得你进过我办公室
Because I don't believe you've ever been in my office before.
没有  没出事
No, nothing's wrong.
我知道这话不该我来说
And I know it's not my place,
但我来告诉你  我觉得你犯了错误
but I'm here to tell you that I think you're making a mistake.
是因为哥伦比亚纪念日不放假的事吗
Is this about me not giving people off for Columbus Day?
你知道不是
You know this isn't about that.
哈维跟丹尼尔说了实话
Harvey laid it on the line with Daniel,
可你没有支持他
and you didn't have his back.
唐娜  从我认识哈维起就一直在支持他
Donna, I've had Harvey's back since the day I met him.
告诉你一声
For your information,
我一发现丹尼尔要做什么
when I found out what Daniel was up to,
就让他保证了合伙人选拔要公开
I had him guarantee partnership was on the table.
而之后你让他把那个位置给了错误的人
And then you let him give it to the wrong man.
那是哈维的问题  不是我的
That is on Harvey, not on me.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
丹尼尔担心哈维不能
Daniel was worried that Harvey couldn't
把律所的利益置于他自身利益之上
put the firm's best interests ahead of his own,
哈维又证明了他顾虑得对
and Harvey proved him right.
也许只是你这么骗自己
Or maybe you're just telling yourself that
因为你不想跟丹尼尔·哈德曼对抗
because you don't want to stand up to Daniel Hardman.
唐娜  你在你的位置  我在我的位置
Donna, there's a reason why you are where you are
都是有道理的
and I am where I am,
因为我们中有个人能看到大局
and that is because one of us sees the bigger picture.
你知道弗莱彻引擎公司的事
You knew about Fletcher Engines?
我知道哈维的好日子会到的
What I know is that Harvey's time will come.
而如果这个小事件能让他考虑别人
And if this little incident gets him to think about other people
有点改变  我会接受的
for a change, then I'll take it.
你起得很早
You're up early.
我起得早是因为没睡着
I'm up early, because I couldn't sleep.
你一晚上去哪了
Where we you all night?
你知道我去哪了
You know where I was.
我在新公寓住
I was staying at my new apartment.
我以为我们已经决定好了
I thought we'd settled this.
你决定了  我还没有
You settled it. I didn't.
我跟你说  那个孩子...
I'm telling you, that kid--
奶奶  从我记事起
Grammy, for as long as I can remember,
你就一直叫他"那孩子"
you've been calling him "That kid"
"那小子"  有时更糟
or "That boy" or worse.
他叫特雷弗
His name is Trevor.
他是我最好的朋友
And he's my best friend.
无论你是否祝福我  我都要做这件事
Look, I'm gonna do this thing with or without your blessing,
但...
but...
有你的祝福更好
it sure would be nice to have it.
好吧  迈克
Okay, Michael.
我不会跟你说谎  假装同意
I'm not gonna lie to you and pretend I approve,
但...
but...
你是大人了  我尊重你的决定
you're a grown man, and I respect your decision.
我爱你  奶奶
I love you, Grammy.
我也爱你
I love you too.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我就需要了解这些
I believe that's all I need to know.
谢谢您花时间面试  皮尔逊女士
Thank you for your time, Ms. Pearson.
我会等您的回信
I will wait to hear from you.
还有一件事
Oh, one more thing--
你父亲知道你来找我求职吗
does your father know you came to me for a job?
我...
I-I--
你真以为我不知道
Did you really think I didn't know
你是罗伯特·赞恩的女儿吗
you were Robert Zane's daughter?
你是因为那个才面试我吗
Is that why you're interviewing me?
如果是的
Because if it is,
我希望我从备选名单上除名
I would like to remove myself from consideration.
你不想给你父亲工作
If you don't want to work for your father,
那是你的事
that's your business.
我雇你是因为我喜欢自己看到的特质
I'm hiring you because I like what I see.
雇我
Hiring me?
周一开始上班  如果没问题的话
You start Monday, if that's not too much trouble.
我会第一个来上班的
I will be the first one in.
你不问我为什么不想为我父亲工作吗
Aren't you gonna ask me why I don't want to work with my father?
我知道原因
I know why.
我有个跟你一样的父亲
I have a dad just like yours.
他也有自己的律所
He has his own law firm?
他是外科医生
He's a surgeon.
但其实是一样的
But it's the same damn thing.
-时间准吗  -时间刚刚好
- How are we on time? - We're perfect.
但我不进去了  你俩去
But I'm not going in there. You two are.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我说过要把麦肯诺的一半业务给你
I said I was giving you 50% of McKernon.
但没说我会保留另一半
I didn't say I was keeping the other 50%.
你终于意识到他们的代理
Oh, so you finally realized they need an upgrade
需要升级了
in representation.
悠着点  弗雷泽
Easy, Frazier.
要不是我救你
You'd still be out cold at that gas station
你还在加油站冻着呢
if I hadn't saved your ass.
我最终总能活着出去的...
Okay, I would have gotten out... eventually.
-我看不会  -我很狡猾的
- Not from where I was standing. - I'm slippery.
我说过  我在高中玩摔跤的
I told you-- I wrestled in high school.
-我查过  他是玩过  -看见了吧
- I checked on that. He did. - See?
现在你要帮他了
Oh, and now you're fighting for him?
那我想这里没我事了
Okay, I guess my job here is done.
等等  你去哪
Wait, where are you going?
我把车开回城里去
I'm taking the car, back to the city.
我们要怎么办
What the hell we suppose to do?
雷在停车场那头等着呢  对吗
Ray is wating on the other side of the parking, isn't he?
你们办完事  他载你们回去
He'll drive you two back when you're done
等等  我有个更好的主意
Wait, you know, I have a better idea.
你带走雷  我们开车
How about you take Ray, we take the car,
回去路上我教迈克开车怎么样
and I'll teach Mike how to drive on the way home.
你真愿意教我
You'd actually do that?
愿意
Yeah, I would.
坚决不行
No way.
你不相信我
You don't trust me?
我就是不信任你
I don't trust you as far as I can throw you,
你是个骗子
you're a god damn fraud.
那是我的话
That's what I said.
哈维  说真的  我保证...
Harvey, seriously, I promise...
好了  我知道
Okay, I know you will.
路易  车被蹭一点
Louis, you make one dent in the car,
迈克重新失业  你办公室门上名字也别要了
Mike's back on the street, your name's off the door.
你觉得他刚才说的是认真的吗
You think he's serious about what he said?
走吧
Come on.
我有点紧张
Just a little nervous,
我感觉像喝了烈酒
cause I feel like I drank the power drink,
里头掺了好多苏打水
has a lot soda in it,
-但其实是坏热狗  -好吧
- actrually, it's a dirty hot dog, - Okay.
医生说那东西升高了我的血压
the doctor says it raise my blood pressure.
一会儿我来说话吧
I would let me to give the talk.